In this clip, we're going to talk about the rule of thirds.
The rule of thirds is basically is a compositional rule of thumb.
In photography, painting, art and any sort of visual medium.
It essentially is, basically this.
You draw two imaginary lines, vertically.
And two imaginary lines, horizontally in an image.
Drawing these lines creates nine separate boxes in an image.
And the idea is, by aligning your, the focus of your design or drawing or video.
Within one of these nine boxes.
You're creating a more visually, aesthetically pleasing shot or image or painting.
Instead of just putting the subject in the dead center of your frame.
Now technically, the dead center is used to make a point.
In terms of photography and video and painting.
And if you put an object in the dead center, it's supposed to be the clear focal point.
It's supposed to be sort of a power pose in my mind.
It's looks like more imposing.
If you throw someone or something into the right corner or the left corner.
As the case maybe.
It changes everything.
It makes it a little bit more visually pleasing.
And it's not really clear, exactly why this is.
It's just the human brain and the human eye.
This point has been trained to accept that this is the correct and most visually pleasing way to frame your picture or drawing.
As the case may be.
So while framing is largely a relative thing.
And if you decide to be off on guard.
And you know, break all the rules.
You can frame your drawings, any way you like.
However, if you want to be taken seriously.
You will follow the principle of the rule of thirds.
Always keeping in mind, your nine separate framing boxes.
In your drawings, designs, photographs, whatever.
That is essentially, what the rule of thirds is.